Ashutosh Kumar

Technical Consultant

I am an experienced IT professional with over 7 years of experience in the software industry, including 3 years of specialized expertise in DevOps. Currently working as a Technical Consultant at Precisely, I am actively seeking a role as a DevOps Engineer where I can apply my extensive skills and drive innovation within the field.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Precisely Software & Data India P. Limited - Technical Consultant Project - EnterWorks July 2022 - PRESENT

 As a Technical Consultant, I manage global EnterWorks installations, ensuring seamless, successful deployments. My responsibilities include careful planning, technical expertise, and proactive communication.

Technologies worked on - SQL Server, Installer, Windows OS

Precisely Software & Data India P. Limited - Software Engineer

Project - Web Mapping Application May 2020 – June 2022

- I created InstallShield installers for a web mapping app, ensuring seamless installations. Managed CI/CD pipelines with TeamCity, reducing manual work by 70% and boosting efficiency.
- Managed Git Continuous Integration (CI) and configured custom runners using Docker.
- Set up a TeamCity project for Checkmarx scans.

Technologies worked on: TeamCity, GIT, PowerShell, Checkmarx, InstallShield, Docker, Windows & Linux OS

Pitney Bowes Software India P. Limited - SDE Intern

Project - Cross Border E-commerce

February 2016 – April 2020

- Automated the software build process using Jenkins, including configuring and managing build jobs, setting up build triggers, integrating with version control systems, and executing build scripts.
- Created and managed branches for software development in version control systems to organize and isolate different features, bug fixes, or releases.

Technologies worked on: Jenkins, SVN

EDUCATION

Uttar Pradesh Technical University, Lucknow
B. Tech in Computer Science and Engineering, Graduated in 2015

PERSONAL PROJECTS

AWS Resource Usage Tracker using shell script

GitHub: https://github.com/AshutoshKumar99/AWSResourceUsage
Running NodeJS Tests/CI with GitHub Actions/Workflow

GitHub: https://github.com/AshutoshKumar99/github-actions-nodejs-tests

ADDRESS: Noida, Sector 66,

Uttar Pradesh Mobile: 9936514482

ashutoshkumar101094@gmail.co

m

www.linkedin.com/in/ashutosh-

kumar-b0084212b

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud Computing: **AWS**CICD: **Jenkins, TeamCity**Containerization: **Docker**Scripting Languages: **Bash**

VCS: **GIT, SVN**IaC Tool: **Terraform**

Configuration Management:

Ansible

Application Server: Apache

Tomcat

Familiar with **GitHub Actions** Operating Systems: **Windows**,

Linux

ACCOMPLISHMENT

R&R Award for outstanding contributions to Cross Border E-commerce at Pitney Bowes.

Thumbs Up Award for outstanding performance on the Web Mapping Application project.

Spot Award from Precisely for exceptional performance on the EnterWorks project at Precisely

CERTIFICATES

HashiCorp Certified: **Terraform Associate AWS Certified Cloud**

Practitioner

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi